[
  {
    "question": "Where was Rebecca Belmore born?",
    "a": "Quebec",
    "b": "Manitoba",
    "c": "Ontario",
    "d": "Saskatchewan",
    "e": "Alberta",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What language does the Lac Seul First Nation speak?",
    "a": "Tlingit",
    "b": "Algonquian",
    "c": "Iroquois",
    "d": "Anishinaabe",
    "e": "Athabaskan",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which Canadian city did Rebecca Belmore attend high school?",
    "a": "Windsor",
    "b": "Thunder Bay",
    "c": "Mississauga",
    "d": "Ottawa",
    "e": "Hamilton",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "With which type of art is Rebecca Belmore MOST associated?",
    "a": "performance art",
    "b": "painting",
    "c": "printmaking",
    "d": "sound art",
    "e": "Earthworks",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tribe was involved in the Kanesatake Resistance?",
    "a": "Onondaga",
    "b": "Seneca",
    "c": "Cayuga",
    "d": "Mohawk",
    "e": "Oneida",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did the Oka Crisis come to an end?",
    "a": "The land was designated a Mohawk reservation.",
    "b": "The National Guard drove protestors off the land.",
    "c": "The federal government purchased the land.",
    "d": "The leader of the protestors was killed.",
    "e": "The tribe signed a treaty with the government.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "By what factor is it estimated that Ayum-ee-aawatch Oomama-mowan: Speaking to their Mother can amplify sounds?",
    "a": "nine times",
    "b": "seven times",
    "c": "five times",
    "d": "two times",
    "e": "thirteen times",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following materials was used in the construction of Ayum-ee-aawatch Oomama-mowan: Speaking to their Mother?",
    "a": "plaster",
    "b": "limestone",
    "c": "tree bark",
    "d": "sandstone",
    "e": "animal hide",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the intended audience of Ayum-ee-aawatch Oomama-mowan: Speaking to their Mother?",
    "a": "native people living on reservations",
    "b": "the land itself",
    "c": "canadian politicians",
    "d": "corporate executives",
    "e": "construction workers building on native land",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is Rebecca Belmore’s work similar to that of Ana Mendieta?",
    "a": "It involved large sculptural components.",
    "b": "It referred to the land as maternal.",
    "c": "It used wood in their construction.",
    "d": "It was constructed in Canada.",
    "e": "It was an Earthwork.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which term did scholar Vanessa Watts coin to describe the notion that the land had a consciousness of its own?",
    "a": "earth-soul",
    "b": "intelligence of the land",
    "c": "terrestrial awareness",
    "d": "nature’s mind",
    "e": "place-thought",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The geological era caused by human activity is called the",
    "a": "Neolithic",
    "b": "Anthropocene",
    "c": "Cenozoic",
    "d": "Steel Age",
    "e": "Tertiary Period",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which term refers to the period in the mid-20th century when carbon emissions dramatically increased?",
    "a": "The Great Acceleration",
    "b": "The First Industrial Revolution",
    "c": "The Second Industrial Revolution",
    "d": "The Factory Age",
    "e": "The Industrial Era",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a location of the installation of Wave Sounds?",
    "a": "Gros Morne National Park",
    "b": "Georgian Bay National Park",
    "c": "Banff National Park",
    "d": "Waterton Lakes National Park",
    "e": "Pukaskwa National Park",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which scholar stated that “Belmore’s work concerns not only what we hear, but how we might truly listen to those sounds”?",
    "a": "Carolee Schneemann",
    "b": "Chris Burden",
    "c": "Canice Hopkins",
    "d": "Kathe Kowalski",
    "e": "Ana Mendieta",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following organizations awarded Mel Chin a fellowship to recognize his artwork?",
    "a": "the Rockefeller Foundation",
    "b": "the MacArthur Fellows Program",
    "c": "the Getty Foundation",
    "d": "the Ford Foundation",
    "e": "the Smithsonian Fellows Program",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mel Chin practices in all of the following artistic mediums EXCEPT",
    "a": "film",
    "b": "ceramics",
    "c": "animation",
    "d": "performance",
    "e": "earthworks",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "See-Saw would best be considered a part of",
    "a": "Pop Art",
    "b": "Romanticism",
    "c": "Minimalism",
    "d": "Expressionism",
    "e": "Cubism",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the PRIMARY function of See-Saw?",
    "a": "critiquing American consumer culture",
    "b": "encouraging social interaction among viewers",
    "c": "expressing the artist’s sorrow",
    "d": "representing the usefulness of new technology",
    "e": "conveying the artist’s environmental message",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which television show did The GALA Committee contribute artwork?",
    "a": "Melrose Place",
    "b": "Seinfeld",
    "c": "Friends",
    "d": "The Simpsons",
    "e": "The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the purpose of the funds raised by the auction of the GALA Committee’s artwork?",
    "a": "to expand the project further",
    "b": "to generate profit for Sotheby’s auction house",
    "c": "to promote the careers of more artists",
    "d": "to raise funds for cancer research",
    "e": "to donate to education charities",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which disaster prompted the creation of the Fundred Project?",
    "a": "the Tohoku Tsunami",
    "b": "the Haitian earthquake in 2010",
    "c": "the 9/11 terrorist attacks",
    "d": "Hurricane Katrina",
    "e": "the Flint Water Crisis",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approximately how many collaborators worked on the Fundred Project?",
    "a": "500,000",
    "b": "5,000",
    "c": "50",
    "d": "50,000",
    "e": "500",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Revival Field PRIMARILY focuses on",
    "a": "problems of industrial pollution",
    "b": "the cultural significance of wildlife",
    "c": "the effects of climate change on ecosystems",
    "d": "sustainable farming techniques",
    "e": "the lifecycles of local plants",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aspect of Revival Field separates it from earlier Earthwork projects?",
    "a": "its use of recycled material",
    "b": "its ecological improvements to the land it was on",
    "c": "its exploration of traditional farming techniques",
    "d": "its focus on incorporating new technology",
    "e": "its abstract geometric form",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary focus of Chin’s film The Arctic Is?",
    "a": "the economic costs of the melting ice caps",
    "b": "the history of Greenland’s natural environment",
    "c": "the dire effects of climate change",
    "d": "the natural beauty of the Arctic",
    "e": "Inuit tradition",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following cities does Jens Danielson NOT describe as being the Arctic?",
    "a": "Dallas",
    "b": "Helsinki",
    "c": "Jakarta",
    "d": "London",
    "e": "Beijing",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where would viewers look at Unmoored?",
    "a": "floating above Times Square",
    "b": "in the entryway to Metropolitan Museum of Art",
    "c": "outside the windows of the Empire State Building",
    "d": "as a billboard in Times Square",
    "e": "scattered across Brooklyn",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Unmoored depict New York as being underwater?",
    "a": "to demonstrate the impact of overfishing",
    "b": "to represent the effects of melting ice caps",
    "c": "to commemorate the Paris Climate Accords",
    "d": "to celebrate the city’s maritime history",
    "e": "to highlight the city’s vulnerability to natural disaster",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which political figure created and stars in An Inconvenient Truth?",
    "a": "George W. Bush",
    "b": "Barack Obama",
    "c": "Al Gore",
    "d": "John Kerry",
    "e": "Hillary Clinton",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  }
]